Guide to the Rice University James A. Baker III Institute for Public Policy records, 1993-2014 UA 114
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University James A. Baker III Institute for Public Policy records
1993-2014
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
James A. Baker III Institute for Public Policy.
UA 114
38.10 Linear Feet 43 boxes
This collection includes records dating from the groundbreaking, founding, and development including but not limited to booklets, correspondence, financial documents, and news clippings of Baker Hall and the Institute for Public Policy.
Biographical / Historical
On June 2, 1992, Dr. Richard J. Stoll, Director for the Center for the Study of Institutions and Values, as well as a professor of Political Science, sent a memo to then Rice President George Rupp. In this memo, Stoll suggested that Rice approach then Secretary of State James A. Baker III for the beginnings of a "James Baker Institute". Rupp responded favorably to Stoll's memo and thus the Baker Institute was born.
On March 31, 1993, Secretary Baker gave a speech accepting Rice's offer of an Institute in his honor. While at Rice where he laid down his ideas on the Baker Institute. In this speech, entitled "Ideas Into Action", in which he charged the Baker Institute to "draw together statesmen, scholars and students...and...build a bridge between the world of ideas and the world of action..." These founding words were later used as the building stones for the external architecture of the building.
Between 1993 and 1994, the Baker Institute was coordinated by John Rogers, former undersecretary for management at the Department of State. In August 1994, Rice appointed a Founding Director for the Institute, distinguished diplomat Ambassador Edward P. Djerejian. Ambassador Djerejian served in this post until June 2022 and was replaced by David M. Satterfield.
On October 20, 1994 ground was broken on the Baker Hall building site. Four U.S. Presidents participated in the ceremony (Gerald Ford, Jimmy Carter, Ronald Reagan, and George H.W. Bush), setting the bipartisan tone that James A. Baker III had madated from the Institute's beginning. More information on the Institute's groundbreaking ceremony can be found in the Inagural Baker Institute report. This was a major step forward for the Institute. As the Founding Director noted: "...the building itself symbolizes, in both form and function, the integrative nature of the Baker Institute. Within its walls the faculty and students of Rice University will interact with visiting scholars and practitioners to address the major issues our nation faces in the future."
The First Associate Director for Academic Programs was selected in 1995 - Dr. Richard Stoll. In January 2001, Dr. Stoll resigned from that position to take on more responsibility as the Associate Dean of Social Sciences at Rice. The current Associate Director is Dr. Allen Matusow.
On October 17, 2003 the Baker Institute celebrated its 10th anniversary with a gala on Jamail Plaza. The gala featured Vice President Richard Cheney as the guest of honor. More than 700 people turned out to raise their glasses in tribute to the occasion.
Largely excerpted from the Baker Institute website, http://bakerinstitute.org/BakerIns/hist_index.htm (accessed on Jan. 9, 2006).
Scope and Contents
Records dating from the groundbreaking, founding, and development of Baker Hall and the Institute for Public Policy. Formats include informational booklets, groundbreaking materials, press releases, invitations to events, videotapes of events, development records, conference materials, and correspondence.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Box 9 stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.
Acquisition Information
These records were gathered by WRC staff in some cases and transferred from the James A. Baker III Institute for Public Policy in other cases.
Related Material
For further information on James A. Baker III Institute for Public Policy, please contact the Institute directly. https://bakerinstitute.org/
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Political culture; Political planning; Social history; Policy sciences; Politics and government
Document Types
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Video recordings; press releases; pamphlets; Ephemera; Correspondence
Places
United States
Subjects (Corporations)
James A. Baker III Institute for Public Policy.
- Series I: Printed materials, 1993-2003, 244867
  - Informational booklets, 244879 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Facility groundbreaking materials, Oct. 1997 [see also Baker Hall info file], 244878 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Building rendering, iconography, 244877 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Status reports, design and construction, 1994-95, 244876 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Annual conferences, 244875 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Invitations / events, 244874 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Baker Institute Study" - see also cataloged copies, 244873 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Baker Institute Report" - see also cataloged copies, 244872 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Press / news releases, 244871 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 10th anniversary celebration, Oct. 17, 2003, 244870 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - James A. Baker III 75th birthday celebration, April 28, 2005, 244869 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Greeting cards, 244868 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Series II: Videotapes (VHS) of Baker Institute events, 1994-2003, 244813
  - "A Forum on the Role of the Secretary of the Treasury;" Sam Donaldson, Paul Gigot, et.al. Oct. 5, 2001 [2 tapes, 2 copies], 244866 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - Energy forum: "Running on Empty? Prospects for Future World Oil Supplies;" May 19, 2000 [3 tapes], 244865 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - Conference on Global Warming keynote address, "Science and Policy;" Robert F. Curl, Sept. 8, 2000, 244864 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - "Turkey: U.S. & Eurasia-Economic, Security and Energy Issues;" Baki Illkin, Dec. 14, 1998, 244863 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - Defense Policy debate, Nov. 18, 1998, 244862 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - Dept. of Electrical Engineering presentation by John Doerr, March 31, 2000, 244861 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - "Greece: Greece's Foreign Policy;" Ambassador Philon, Jan. 11, 1999, 244860 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - "The Middle East Peace Process;" Amre Moussa, March 22, 2000, 244859 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - Prince El Hassan bin Talal, n.d., 244858 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - "Energy and the Russian Economy: A Look Ahead;" Mikhail Fridman, Peter Aven, March 20, 2003, 244857 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - "The Relationship Between Literature and Public Policy in Latin America," n.d., 244856 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - "Eduard Shevardnadze;" n.d., 244855 (Box 4, Folder -)
  - Leadership Houston Seminar, Jan. 13, 1999 [2 tapes], 244854 (Box 4, Folder -)
  - "Religion and Public Policy-With God on Their Side;" Bill Martin & others, Oct. 30, 2001 [2 tapes], 244853 (Box 4, Folder -)
  - "His Excellency the President of the Republic of Rwanda Paul Kagame," March 6, 2003, 244852 (Box 4, Folder -)
  - "The President's Lawyer, Alberto R. Gonzales," Sept. 7, 2001, 244851 (Box 4, Folder -)
  - "Argument Without End: In Search of Answers to the Vietnam Tragedy," Robert McNamara, J. Blight, R. Bigham, Feb. 28, 2000, 244850 (Box 4, Folder -)
  - U.S.-Syrian press conference-Edward P. Djerjian, May 23, 2002, 244849 (Box 4, Folder -)
  - "The Future of the Space Program and Space Policy;" Ralph M. Hall, Aug. 26, 2002, 244848 (Box 4, Folder -)
  - "Ten Years After Oslo: The Rabin Legacy in Today's Middle East;" Clifton Morgan, Dali Rabin-Pelossof, March 25, 2003, 244847 (Box 4, Folder -)
  - "Strategic Energy Policy Challenges for the 21st Century;" Edward Morse, Amy Jaffe & others, April 26, 2001, 244846 (Box 4, Folder -)
  - "North Korea: Economic Status and Future Plans;" Young Gun Jon, Hgong Chu Li, Suchan Chac, Feb. 19, 2001, 244845 (Box 4, Folder -)
  - "Colombia-Challenges and Prospects for the Future;" n.d., 244844 (Box 4, Folder -)
  - "With God on Their Side: Religion and American Foreign Policy;" n.d., 244843 (Box 4, Folder -)
  - "Mexican Energy in the 21st Century;" R. Mosbacher, R. Leos, T. McLarty, June 22, 2001, 244842 (Box 4, Folder -)
  - "Moving Beyond the War on Drugs;" Martin, Trace, Wodak, Oscapella, Cohen, April 11, 2002 [4 tapes], 244841 (Box 5, Folder -)
  - Vladimir V. Putin, President of the Russian Federation and George H.W. Bush, Nov. 14, 2001, 244840 (Box 5, Folder -)
  - "Enron: What Happens Next;" April 4, 2002, 244839 (Box 5, Folder -)
  - "America After 9/11;" Thomas L. Friedman, Sept. 27, 2002, 244838 (Box 5, Folder -)
  - "Mexico: The Policy and Politics of Modernization;" HE Carlos Salinas de Gortari, May 15, 2002, 244837 (Box 5, Folder -)
  - "America and the World Today;" Richard C. Holbrooke, Oct. 29, 2002, 244836 (Box 5, Folder -)
  - "Beyond Sept. 11 and Al Qaeda: The Kashmir Conflict;" Feb. 28, 2002, 244835 (Box 5, Folder -)
  - "The Legacy of the Nuremburg Trials;" Stein, Ferencz, Bass, Fowler, Morrow, Feb. 12, 2003, 244834 (Box 5, Folder -)
  - The Americas Project panel discussion-Barnes, Shifter, Weyland, Zarazoga, Oct. 27, 2002, 244833 (Box 5, Folder -)
  - White House Fellowship recruiting event, Dec. 18, 2002, 244832 (Box 5, Folder -)
  - "France: European Unity and the Threat on U.S. Interests;" Francois de l'Estang, Dec. 7, 1999, 244831 (Box 5, Folder -)
  - "The Ideas that Conquered the World: Peace, Democracy and Free Markets;" Michael Mandelbaum, Jan. 24, 2003, 244830 (Box 5, Folder -)
  - "Crisis in America;" press conference with Edward P. Djerjian, Sept. 11, 2001, 244829 (Box 5, Folder -)
  - "Train Up a Child-Religious Conservatives and the Struggle Over Schooling;" Wm. Martin & others, Feb. 5, 2002, 244828 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - "The Americas Project 2002;" Keynote speaker Roger Noriega, Oct. 27, 2002, 244827 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - "Live in America Town Hall Meeting;" Sam Donaldson, April 26, 2002, 244826 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - "Mongolia's Neighbors: Russia, China & others;" Nambar Enkhbayar, Nov. 19, 2001, 244825 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - "Georgia: Evolution of a Strategic Partner;" Zurab Zhavania, Jan. 14, 1999, 244824 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - "Literature, Poetry, and Public Policy: Interaction and Synthesis;" Dominique de Vellepin & Shashi Tharoor, Feb. 10, 1999, 244823 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - "Is America Still Unprepared and In Danger?" Stephen E. Flynn, Nov. 6, 2002, 244822 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - "The Americas Project 2000;" keynote speaker Orlando Sanchez, Oct. 2, 2000, 244821 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - "The Americas Project 2000;" keynote speaker Domingo Cavallo, Nov. 3, 2000, 244820 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - "The Americas Project 2000" panel discussion, Oct. 2, 2000, 244819 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - U.S.-Syrian press conference with Edward P. Djerjian, May 23, 2002, 244818 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - "The Czech Republic and Europe: The Czech Republic's View of Future Transatlantic Relations;" Vladimir Spidla, July 17, 2003, 244817 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - "Societal Responses to Climate Change;" Neal Lane, April 25, 2002, 244816 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - International Symposium on Afghanistan keynote-Djerjian, Pietton, Shahryan, Roy, Nov. 18, 2002 [1/2], 244815 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - "The Asia Presentation;" n.d., 244814 (Box 6, Folder -)
- Series III: Reports and conferences, 244809
  - Final Report on Media for Inuagural Conference, 1995, 244812 (Box 7, Folder -)
  - Annual Conference Media Plan, 1997, 244811 (Box 7, Folder -)
  - Studies for annual conferences, 1997-1999, 244810 (Box 8, Folder -)
- Series IV: Newsclippings, 1993-2012, 244803
  - Newsclips, 1993-1998, 244808 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Newsclips, 1999-2000, 244807 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Newsclips, 2001-2002, 244806 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Newsclips, 2003-2007, 244805 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Newsclips, 2008-, 244804 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Series V: 25th Anniversary Gala, 2018
  - Event "A Quarter Century Making History" invitation, program, badge, postcard, levels of support, stamps (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Series VI: Building Plans and Architectural Drawings
  - Drawer 127: Oversized building plans and architectural drawings
    General
    See Rice University Architectural drawings, oversize manuscript material, maps and photographs (UA 226) https://txarchives.org/ricewrc/finding_aids/00761.xml
  - BIPP: B. Stein Building Files, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - BIPP Building, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Building Dedication, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Captain Baker's Wood Paneling, 1997-2001 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - BIPP Berlin Wall Relocation, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Series VII: Leadership Committee
  - Leadership Committee Handbook, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Committee Meeting April 8, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Conditions Governing Access
    This folder is restricted for the life of the creator plus 50 years.
  - Committee Meeting September 30, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Committee Meeting February 22, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Series VIII: BIPP General Operations
  - BIPP Mission Statement, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Talking Points-BIPP and Climate Change, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - First Steps Memos and Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Index for Speeches, Videos, and Interviews, 1993-1995 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - BIPP Historical, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Annual Reports, 1995-1997 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - BIPP Memorabilia, Lists, and Correspondence, 1995-2007 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - BIPP Board of Advisors, 1997-2005 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Think Tank Directory Entry, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - BIPP Energy Forum, 2002-2007 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Enron Corporation, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - BIPP Student Involvement, 2004-2007 (Box 10, Folder 21)
- Series IX: General Correspondence
  - BIPP: Correspondence, 1994-2004 (Box 10, Folder 22)
- Series X: BIPP Policies
  - BIPP: Tax Policy Program, 1995-2005 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - BIPP: Health Policy Program, 2004-2007 (Box 10, Folder 24)
- Series XI: Publications
  - Subseries A: BIPP Reports
    - Baker Institute for Public Policy Reports, Numbers 1-8, 1995-1997 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Baker Institute for Public Policy Reports, Numbers 9-13, 1998-2000 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Baker Institute for Public Policy Reports, Numbers 14-18, 2000-2002 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Baker Institute for Public Policy Reports, Numbers 20 and 21, 2003-2004 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - China's Growing Energy Dependence: The Costs and Policy Implications of Supply Alternatives, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - The Israeli-Syrian Dialogue: A One-Way Ticket to Peace?, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - An Alternative Pipeline Strategy in the Persian Gulf, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Getting to the Territorial Endgame of an Israeli-Palestinian Peace Settlement, 2010 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Subseries B: BIPP Studies
    - Baker Institute for Public Policy Studies No. 1-10, 1995-1999 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Baker Institute for Public Policy Studies No. 11-23, 1999-2003 (Box 10, Folder 34)
      No. 13 and 21 are not present
    - A Proposal for Immigration Reform, 2007 (Box 10, Folder 35)
- Series XII: BIPP Events
  - BIPP Events, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - BIPP Events, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - BIPP Events, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - BIPP Events, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - BIPP Events, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - BIPP Events, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - BIPP Events, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - BIPP Events, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - BIPP Events, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - BIPP Events, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - BIPP Events, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - BIPP Events, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - BIPP Events, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - BIPP Events, 2006 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - BIPP Events, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - BIPP Events, 2008 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Comprehensive Speakers List, 1994-2003 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - BIPP Invitations, 1999-2007 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - BIPP: Outstanding Invitations, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - BIPP: Tenth Anniversary Event, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - BIPP: Collaborative Programs, 2003-2008 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - BIPP Event Parking Issues, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Series XIII: Publicity and Media
  - BIPP: Jewish Herald Voice Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - BIPP: M. Cinelli (Media Coverage), 1998 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - BIPP: Media, 2006 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - BIPP: Publicity, 2008 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Series XIV: Development
  This series is restricted for the life of the creator plus 50 years..
  - Subseries A: Fundraising
    - Baker "Center" Planning, 1992-1993 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Institute Planning, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Baker Institute Campaign Prospect Lists, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Baker Institute Campaign Notebook, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - External Affairs Committee Meeting Materials (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - BIPP Reception at River Oaks May 25, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - BIPP Foundation, Corporate Support, 1993-1994 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - BIPP Institute Documents, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - BIPP Executive Summary, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Building Dedication/Fundraising Dinner Annual Conference, 1 of 2, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Building Dedication/Fundraising Dinner Annual Conference, 2 of 2, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Subseries B: Gifts
    - BIPP Gifts, 1993-1997 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - BIPP Gifts, 1998-1999 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - BIPP Gifts, 2000-2002 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - BIPP Gifts, 2002-2005 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - BIPP Gifts, 2006-2008 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - BIPP Infrastructure and Maintenance Costs, 1996-1997 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - BIPP Fellowships, 1996-2008 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - BIPP Budget Information, 1998-2004 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - BIPP Roundtable, 2000-2004 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - BIPP Potential Donors, 2002-2008 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - BIPP Fundraising Efforts, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - BIPP Baker Botts Partnership, 2003-2007 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - BIPP Donations in honor of JAB's 75th Birthday, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - BIPP U.S. Mexico Border Project (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - BIPP Development Reports, 2006-2008 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - BIPP Kelly Funds, 2007 (Box 13, Folder 27)
- Series XV: Edward P. Djerejian
  This series is restricted for the life of the creator plus 50 years.
  - Rememberance of Things Present Manuscript, undated (Box 13, Folder 28)
    Though mispelled the title reflects the actual spelling on the manuscript.
  - Djerejian Retirement Speech, undated (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Zodrow's Tax Reform Book Preface, undated (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Historic Papers, 1967-1994 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - HHE Shipments, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Governance Procedures, 1994-1996 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Ambassador Edward Djerejian Photographs, 1994-2016 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Take Home Folder, 1996-1997 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Faculty Advisory Committee, 1997-2000 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Macrocosm Proposal, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Graduate Student Association, 1998-1999 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Meetings with Faculty, 1998-2001 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Annual Report of the Institute of Biosciences and Bioengineering, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Korea Energy Economics Institute Collaboration, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - BIPP Jones School Collaboration, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - BIPP Endowed Positions, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - BIPP Spanos Collaboration, 1999-2000 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - National Center for Financial Engineering and Economics, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Vietnam Trip-Professor Zeff, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Research and Programs-Brito, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Eisenhower Institute and BIPP, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - CSIS Collaboration on Trade Policy, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - The Connexions Project, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Meeting with Professor Durani, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Economics and BIPP-Hartley, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Middle East Peace Initiative, 2002-2008 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Changing Minds Winning Peace: A New Strategic Direction for U.S. Public Diplomacy in the Arab & Muslim World, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - McNair Center, 2017 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Puentes Consortium, 2017 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Gala Index, 2017 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Association of Rice Alumni Gold Medal, 2009 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Kuwait Program Development Briefing, 2013 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Subseries A: Correspondence and Communications
    - BIPP: EPD Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - BIPP: EPD Correspondence, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - BIPP: EPD Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - BIPP: EPD Correspondence, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - BIPP: EPD Correspondence, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - BIPP: EPD Correspondence, 2001-2005 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - BIPP: EPD Correspondence, 2006-2008 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - EPD Emails, 1 of 2, 1995-1996 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - EPD Emails, 2 of 2, 1995-1996 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - EPD Emails In, 1995-1999 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - EPD Emails Out, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Requests from Foreign Think Tanks and Universities for cooperation with BIPP, 1996-2001 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Environmental Policy with Peter Hartley, 1998-1999 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Terry Sullivan, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Vice President Pence Visit Communications, 2019 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Subseries B: Hiring Correspondence
    - Will Clayton Fellow, 1998-2000 (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Baker Institute Fellows, 1998-2001 (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Environmental Economics-E. Berman, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - McClellan, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - Merkx/Remner, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Health and Economics Chair Candidates, 2000-2001 (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - Gerrard/Gibbons Hires, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - Saldivar, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 42)
    - Center for Health and Biosciences Director Search, 1 of 2, 2019 (Box 14, Folder 43)
    - Center for Health and Biosciences Director Search, 2 of 2, 2019-2021 (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - Subseries C: Rice University Correspondence
    - Leadership Rice, 1996-2000 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Doctor Brito, 1997-2001 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - University Policy, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Rice Public Affairs Committee, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Rice: The Next Century Campaign, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Post Harvey Committee for Rice Engagement with Houston, 2017 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - V2C2 Global Strategy for Rice University 1 of 2, 2017 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - V2C2 Global Strategy for Rice University 2 of 2, 2017-2018 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Subseries D: Early Career
    - News Clippings, 1974-1994 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - White House Press Briefings, 1 of 3, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - White House Press Briefings, 2 of 3, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - White House Press Briefings, 3 of 3, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - White House Press Briefings, 1 of 3, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - White House Press Briefings, 2 of 3, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - White House Press Briefings, 3 of 3, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Push-Arar: Armenian General Benevolent Union 80th Anniversary Booklet, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Subseries E: EPD Trips
    - New York, Princeton, and Boston September 25-29, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Princeton/Washington November 9-11, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Stanford, California February 12-14, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Atlanta February 27-28, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Washington-Center for Middle East Peace Conference May 31, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Pensacola/Washington June 15-21, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Consultations on Middle East in the Netherlands July 13, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 17)